Ethan Schneider

Summary

I'm a 2nd-year Robotics Ph.D. student at the Georgia Institute of Technology, advised by Prof. Sonia Chernova as a part of the RAIL Lab. I am working on developing algorithms for large scale multi-agent Task and Motion Planning (TAMP) for environments such as warehouses and search-and-rescue scenarios. Additionally, my research includes enabling users to query a multi-agent system's decision making using Explainable AI (XAI) techniques, so that users better understand a system's decision or diagnose failures or suboptimal behaviors.

Education

Ph.D in Robotics

Georgia Institute of Technology · GPA: 3.9/4.0

·

B.S in Mechatronics Engineering

Kennesaw State University · GPA: 4.0/4.0

Marietta, GA Aug 2018 - Aug 2022

Aug 2022 - Present

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

Atlanta, GA

Atlanta, GA

Georgia Institute of Technology

Jan 2023 - Present

- Developing Explainable AI (XAI) techniques for explaining multi-agent system decision making for endusers.
- Developing interleaved task and motion planning (TAMP) algorithms for large scale structured environments.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Marietta, GA

Kennesaw State University

Sep 2021 - Aug 2022

- Developed a 3 DOF Soft Delta Robot using open-loop control with a MATLAB Simulink model to generate motion paths.
- Developed a Python front and back-end for variable power supply control, sensor reading, and Scan Conversion algorithm for Intravascular Ultrasound (IVUS) medical imaging technology in collaboration with researchers at Georgia Tech.

Co-Op Software Engineer

Smyrna, GA

Georgia Tech Research Institute

Jan 2021 - Aug 2022

- Developed C# .NET 6.0 Framework radar and aircraft system simulator applications for customers and learned both WPF and MVVM architecture for developing graphical user interfaces.
- Developed and maintained Minikube Docker containers for working and building with Latex documentation.

Electrical Engineering Intern

Kennesaw, GA

Freedom Electronics

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Wrote several test-procedure documents for workers to analyze PCBs, which allowed new types of boards to be worked on.
- Fixed several test apparatuses involving electronics and embedded systems.

Publications

- Schneider, E., Wu, D., Das, D. and Chernova, S., 2024. CE-MRS: Contrastive Explanations for Multi-Robot Systems. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters.
- Garcia, M., Esquen, A.C., Sabbagh, M., Grace, D., Schneider, E., Ashuri, T., Voicu, R.C., Tekes, A. and Amiri Moghadam, A.A., 2024. Soft Robots: Computational Design, Fabrication, and Position Control of a Novel 3-DOF Soft Robot. Machines, 12(8), p.539.

Teaching Experience

• BridgeUP STEM Program 2024: Volunteered and taught in the Bridge-up STEM 🗹 program to introduce basic AI concepts to select female high-school students from various schools across Atlanta.

Professional Service

 $\circ\,$ Reviewer for: AAAI 2024 Fall Symposium on AI for Aging in Place

Leadership and Team Roles

Vice President	$Marietta, \ GA$
KSU Solar Vehicle Team	2021 - 2022
Computer Science Team Lead	Marietta, GA
KSU Solar Vehicle Team	2019-2022

Academic Achievements

 $\circ\,$ Outstanding Undergraduate Research Award from Kennesaw State University

Skills

Languages: Python \cdot C++ \cdot Latex

Platforms/Tools: $ROS \cdot ROS2 \cdot PyTorch \cdot Docker$